What does it take to find a lost love?
Slumdog Millionaire is a drama, romance film directed by Danny Boyle.
A teenager reflects on his life after being accused of cheating on the
Indian version of "Who Wants to be a Millionaire?".
Older Jamal, played by Dev Patel.
Older Latika, played by Freida Pinto.
Older Salim, played by Madhur Mittal.
Prem, played by Anil Kapoor.
Javed, played by Mahesh Manjrekar.
Sergeant Srinivas, played by Saurabh Shukla.
Slumdog Millionaire is a 2008 British drama film that is a loose adaptation
of the novel Q & A (2005) by Indian author Vikas Swarup.
It narrates the story of 18-year-old Jamal Malik from the Juhu slums of Mumbai.
Starring Dev Patel in his film debut as Jamal, and filmed in India, it was directed by Danny Boyle, written by
Simon Beaufoy, and produced by Christian Colson, with Loveleen Tandan credited as co-director.
As a contestant on Kaun Banega Crorepati, a Hindi Indian version of Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?, Jamal surprises everyone by answering every question correctly so far, winning ₹1 crore
($USD210,000, equivalent to around $300,000 in 2023), and he is one question away from winning the grand prize of ₹2 crore ($USD420,000, equivalent to around $590,000 in 2023).
Accused of cheating, he recounts his life story to the police,
illustrating how he was able to answer each question.
After its world premiere at the Telluride Film Festival and later screenings at the Toronto International Film Festival and the London Film Festival, Slumdog
Millionaire had a nationwide release in United Kingdom on 9 January 2009, in India on 23 January 2009, and in the United States on 25 January 2009.
Regarded as a sleeper hit, Slumdog Millionaire was widely acclaimed, praised for its plot,
soundtrack, cinematography, editing, direction, and performances (especially Patel's).
It was nominated for 10 Academy Awards in 2009 and won 8—the most of any 2008
film—including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Adapted Screenplay.
It won seven BAFTA Awards including Best Film, five
Critics' Choice Awards and four Golden Globes.
However, reception in India and among Indian diaspora was mixed, and the film was the
subject of controversy over its depiction of poverty in India and other issues.
The Hindustan Times called it "an assault on Indian self-esteem".
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, slum,
cheating, suspicion, mumbai (bombay), india.
The tone is emotional.